var questions = [
  {
    num: 1,
    question: "Why seed plot technique of potato is used?",
    answer: "To produce virus free seed.",
    options: [
      "To produce fungi free seed",
      "To produce nematode free seed",
      "To produce virus free seed.",
      "All of the above",
    ],
  },
  {
    num: 2,
    question: "What is the color of breeder seed tag?",
    answer: "Golden Yellow",
    options: ["White", "Golden Yellow", "Red", "Blue"],
  },

  {
    num: 3,
    question: "What is the average SMR of paddy?",
    answer: "1:70-1:80",
    options: ["1:70-1:80", "1:20", "1:100", "1:30-1:60"],
  },

  {
    num: 4,
    question: "Biologically, seed is a matured?",
    answer: "Ovule",
    options: ["Fruit", "Ovary", "Capsule", "Ovule"],
  },

  {
    num: 5,
    question: "What is the inner integument of the seed called?",
    answer: "Tegmen",
    options: ["Testa", "Tegmen", "Epithelium", "Micropyle"],
  },

  {
    num: 6,
    question: "Hot water treatment of seed is useful for control of?",
    answer: "Loose smut",
    options: ["Powdery mildew", "Covered", "Rust", "Loose smut"],
  },

  {
    num: 7,
    question: "Tetrazolium test is used to determine?",
    answer: "Seed viability",
    options: [
      "Seed quality",
      "Seed viability",
      "Seed purity",
      "Seed germination",
    ],
  },

  {
    num: 8,
    question: "Which seed has blue coloured tag on bag?",
    answer: "Certified seed",
    options: [
      "Certified seed",
      "Breeder seed",
      "Foundation seed",
      "Nucleus seed",
    ],
  },

  {
    num: 9,
    question:
      "For accuracy of agriculture experiments,what lavel of probablity is accepted?",
    answer: "5%",
    options: ["10%", "100%", "50%", "5%"],
  },

  {
    num: 10,
    question: "The cut of a crop after it reches maturity is called ?",
    answer: "Hervesting",
    options: ["Cutting", "Hervesting", "Threshing", "Winnowing"],
  },

  {
    num: 11,
    question: "Single cotyledon of jowar is called?",
    answer: "Scutellum",
    options: ["Coleorhiza", "Husk", "Scutellum", "Coleoptile"],
  },

  {
    num: 12,
    question:
      "Which of the following is a major acid used in acid seed scarification?",
    answer: "Sulfuric acid",
    options: [
      "Sulfuric acid",
      "Ammonium sulphate",
      "Nitric acid",
      "Hydrochloric acid",
    ],
  },

  {
    num: 13,
    question: "Father of seed technology?",
    answer: "Badrinarayan barwale",
    options: ["Agnes arber", "Gregor mendel", "Robart", "Badrinarayan barwale"],
  },

  {
    num: 14,
    question:
      "The cotyledons are pushed above the ground and the germination is called?",
    answer: "Epigeal",
    options: ["Matured Seed", "Epigeal", "Endosperm", "Hypogeal"],
  },

  {
    num: 15,
    question: "Which is the following is not an endospermic seed?",
    answer: "Gram",
    options: ["Gram", "potato", "Rice", "Maize"],
  },

  {
    num: 16,
    question: "The seed multiplication ratio of potato?",
    answer: "1:4",
    options: ["1:10", "1:1", "1:4", "1:8"],
  },

  {
    num: 17,
    question: "Foundation seed purity percentage is?",
    answer: "99%",
    options: ["80%", "99.5%", "100%", "99%"],
  },

  {
    num: 18,
    question: "National seed corporation was established in which year?",
    answer: "1963",
    options: ["1963", "1937", "1958", "1934"],
  },

  {
    num: 19,
    question: "What is the color of foundation seed bag tag?",
    answer: "White",
    options: ["Green", "White", "Blue", "Purple"],
  },

  {
    num: 20,
    question: "ICAR established in which year?",
    answer: "1929",
    options: ["1934", "1957", "1929", "1948"],
  },
];
